[theme music]
[Lisbon]
'You're gonna like this one.
It's unusual.'
'You are never gonna guess
how the victim was found.'
Oh, really?
[animal roars]
That is unusual.
Panthera tigris,
if I'm not mistaken.
And there's soft loamy soil
around here
easily worked.
Ergo, a hungry tiger
dug up the body.
Not fair. Uh, there's
a big cat sanctuary around here.
A drunk guy broke in,
freed the tigers
including the one
that discovered our victim.
From the general
state of calm, I take it
that all the tigers
have been rounded up?
As far as you know.
[tigers growling]
[Patrick]
'Hello, kitty-cat.'
[growling continues]
Hard to believe
it's a man-eater.
It was still clawing up
the ground when they got here.
Come on.
[growling continues]
The coroner's investigator
thinks it's suffocation.
Looks like the victim
was killed somewhere else
and then buried here,
based on the lividity pattern.
Oh. Plus there's
a wheelbarrow track here.
Oh, yeah.
Yeah, that, too.
Who was he?
John Doe.
No wallet, no ID.
Well, don't fret.
Rich dead men don't go
unclaimed for very long.
Rich? He's wearing hemp.
He certainly is.
And who wears hemp?
Other than rich men
and medieval peasants?
Yeah, this one's
been reupholstered.
Check out
that tight jawline.
He's certainly not
a medieval peasant.
Face-lift?
I'm guessing.
'Oh. It's a
black diamond wedding band.'
'That's a current trend.
Am I right?'
Looks like he was dieting.
Check out his belt.
[Patrick]
'Yeah. Rapid weight loss.'
Could be dieting.
Could be something else.
[inhales deeply]
Ew!
That's not decomp.
What is that?
[exhales]
The smell of desperation?
Got a match
on our John Doe.
Archer Braddock.
Local car dealer.
Wife and two children.
His wife filed
a missing persons last night.
It says Braddock
had stage 4 bone cancer.
Killing a man
that's already dying.
That's a little redundant,
don't you think?
[man on radio]
'Be advised that
one tiger is still outstanding.'
- 'They made a mistake..'
- What did he say?
...counting the tigers.
There's still one on the loose!
We'll meet you back
at the CBI.
[indistinct chatter]
You are a cool customer.
You think you can
outrun a tiger?
I don't have to. I just have
to run faster than you.
[instrumental music]
[theme music]
[music continues]
[instrumental music]
[baby crying]
[crying continues]
[female #1]
'It's okay, honey.'
[crying continues]
Sorry.
Excuse me.
You ready to be a daddy?
That's gonna be you soon.
Oh no. I can cry
much louder than that.
Where's Cho?
I haven't seen him yet.
Coroner investigator's report.
Putting the TOD between eight
at night and two in morning.
That's a pretty big window.
What did the coroner say
about cause of death?
Uh, she didn't, she's dealing
with a multi-victim
pile-up on the I-80.
No coroner. Alright,
what about motive, suspects?
Braddock had a lot of money.
He had to have had enemies.
Braddock owned
three luxury car dealerships
but when he found out
he was dying
he sold his stake to his
employees at a discount.
The man was kind of a saint.
Do we have any leads?
Braddock wascarrying
a pocket calendar.
His last appointment
before his murder
was at 4:17 p.m.
Pretty specific time.
The entry just says
"Treatment."
- Doctor's treatment?
- I don't know.
And a lot of entries like that
over the last few weeks
each one at a weird time.
I'll go and talk
to the wife about it.
You two stay here
and keep pushing.
And tellCho to
get his ass to work.
[instrumental music]
[snoring]
[music continues]
Good morning, Kimball Cho.
- Good morning.
- Hmm?
That smells good.
It's hand-pressed French roast.
Mmm.
[cap pops]
[pills rattle]
Hey, those are mine.
It's for pain.
I've got pain.
- No, you don't.
- Mmm.
Don't be so stingy.
I'm not stingywith you, am I?
No.
No, you're not.
Mmm!
[instrumental music]
[cell phone rings]
Um-uh.
[phone ringing continues]
No.
No, no, no, no, no.
Not-no, not now.
- It might be work.
- Oh-ah.
[ringing continues]
Ah, that can't be right.
My alarm didn't go off.
Oh. That's because
I turned your alarm off.
I thought you could use
some more sleep.
[sighs]
Damn it, Summer,
I'm late for work.
Lisbon's gonna be
somad at you.
Scary.
No. No. I'm never
late for work.
Well, maybe
it's a good thing.
I mean, it's a...new experience.
You know?
I gotta get ready.
[car approaching]
[Lisbon]
'Looks like somebody's
in for a big inheritance.'
Mm, I suppose, if you go
for that sort of thing.
You mean money?
I'll take health any day.
Once the game's over,
the king and the pawn
go back into the same box.
[doorbell rings]
Shall we?
We're with the CBI.
I'm Agent Teresa Lisbon.
This is Patrick Jane.
- Uh, can we come in?
- Yeah.
[door clicks]
Uh..
Are you Liesl?
That's right.
We're sorry for your loss.
I don't...want to talk
about it.
Of course you don't...uh, maybe
you can TO us
to someone in charge.
You sound like my dad.
- TO?
- Car sales lingo.
- Who manages the house?
- Helen.
Your mother?
Stepmother, I'm guessing.
She's upstairs...in bed.
Could you ask her to come down
and talk to us?
She can't handle
the stairs right now.
She's too weak.
Helen has cancer, too.
Welcome to the house of fun.
That's how I met Archer.
We were attending
a cancer support group.
How long ago was that?
Nine months ago.
I know it sounds
a little...strange
but it was quite
a romantic courtship.
And a short one.
Well, that's what happens
when you're living
with an expiration date.
The wedding was two months ago.
Liesl was a bridesmaid.
'So beautiful.'
We knew we might not have
a lot of time together
but it wasn't supposed
to end like this.
According to his calendar
your husband had
multiple appointments for
treatments
over the past few weeks.
Who was he being treated by?
Uh, Dr. Scheck.
Archer was taking part in an
experimental drug protocol.
Human guinea pig time.
Uh, can I help you
find something?
Oh, I'm just fishing around.
Who is this handsome young man
standing off to the side here?
That's my brother Aden.
Archer's oldest.
- Where's Aden?
- Oh, no idea.
He left the house after
a fight with Archer last year.
They had a...
contentious relationship.
How would you know?
You didn't even know dad then.
[Helen]
'She'll be okay.'
It's been a tough day.
You can imagine.
Excuse me.
Mm-hmm.
Mrs. Braddock, can you think of
anybody
who may have wanted
to harm your husband?
No. I can't.
[dramatic music]
[crying softly]
Uh..
Do you mind if I
help myself to some tea?
Sure.
Thanks.
[clattering]
I'm trying to figure
something out.
You might be able
to help me. Um..
Clearly, your father liked to
live in the lap of luxury here
but when I saw him,
he looked like he was
headed on a pilgrimage
to an ashram in the Punjab.
Yep.
All hemp and natural fibers.
'He got into it
a couple weeks ago.'
He said that he wanted
his outside to bear testimony
to what was happening
in the inside.
Wh-what was happening
on the inside?
My dad was getting healthy.
The cancer was going away.
That's what he said.
Wrong.
Interesting.
Do you know who killed
your father?
If I did,
they wouldn't be breathing.
That's a dangerous path.
Did Aden love him?
Yeah.
It's just..
complicated.
Your father kicked him out,
didn't he?
My dad is
a recovering alcoholic.
Was.
It runs in the family...
addiction.
For Aden, it was drugs.
Dad said that Aden
had to hit bottom
before he could rise up.
[kettle whistling]
Music to my ears.
[whistling continues]
Where would I
find the tea?
First cabinet.
Okay.
[inhales deeply]
'That's dad's tea.'
[rattles]
[lid pops]
[inhales deeply]
Ew!
[laughs]
Yeah, I bet you never
smelled that before.
No, not since this morning.
Where did your father
find this?
No idea.
It was his new fav.
Jane...we need to go and talk
to Braddock's doctor.
Is that the smell from, uh--
Yes, it is.
You, uh..
...might want to bury that.
Deep.
[chuckles]
'Bye.'
The victim's son
had a rap sheet.
Aden Braddock.
Disorderly conduct,
misdemeanor theft.
Looks like the kid
went a little bit wild
after his dad
threw him out.
- Do we know where he lives?
- No.
But the social security
trace shows him working
at a banquet hall
in Agua Blanca.
We also got his cell phone
number, too.
Wait, I've that number before
in the victim's call log.
[mouse clicking]
Archer Braddock called
his son at 7:45 p.m.
It was the last call he made.
And Braddock's wife told Lisbon
that they had
a contentious relationship.
Oh. Good morning, Cho.
- Hey.
- Everything okay?
I just, uh,
overslept my alarm.
Yeah, well, don't get
too comfortable.
We got a lead
on the victim's son.
- Catch you up on the way out.
- Alright.
[cap pops]
[dramatic music]
[music continues]
CBI. Looking
for Aden Braddock.
'That guy.'
[tray clatters]
'Stop, Aden.'
[glasses shatter]
[dramatic music]
Stop! Police!
[groans]
[trays clatter]
[intense music]
[grunts]
Damn it.
[indistinct conversations]
Hi.
Oh, you-you must be
the CBI people.
I'm Betsy Firth,
nurse administrator.
I'm Patrick Jane.
I'm a consulting, uh,
consultant.
And I'm Agent Lisbon.
She's a detective.
Dr. Scheck will be
with you in a minute.
We were all very saddened
to hear about Archer Braddock.
I pulled his files in case
Dr. Scheck
needs to consult them.
Well, thank you, Betsy.
That's very efficient of you.
Mm. Well, we try.
Come on in.
Dr. Scheck, the CBI people
are here to see you.
[Lisbon]
'We just wanted to ask you
a few questions'
'about Archer Braddock .'
Oh, I was very sorry
to hear about that.
We deal with death every day
here but not like that.
It's...awful.
Awful, yes...uh, what's the drug
you're testing here?
Osevent. It's a
bone cancer treatment.
It has the potential
to extend millions of lives.
And earn millions of dollars.
Well, that's not
why we developed it.
No? Why not?
Do you save lives
for the money?
Well, folks are pretty much dead
by the time we show up.
Uh, best we can hope for
is to catch the killer.
Did you kill Archer Braddock?
I'll be talking toyou
from now on.
Yes. I just have
a few questions
about Mr. Braddock's
last appointment.
Hmm. Okay. Uh, Betsy.
I laid out the Braddock file
in consult room 2.
Follow me.
I'll just, uh,
wait out here.
[speaking inaudibly]
The Braddock file
...daily report.
And when you're done, you need
to sign these intake forms.
[pen clicks]
Any new patients today?
Four. Newly cleared
and qualified.
I don't know how you do it.
So how can I help you,
agent?
Uh, Mr. Braddock's
last appointment
was he acting strangely at all?
Not that I recall, no.
Did he say anything
unusual
or mention where he was going
after the appointment?
Let me check his file.
It was just
yesterday afternoon.
Yesterday? No, no, no. Uh.
Braddock's last drug treatment
was two days ago in the morning.
According to his calendar,
he had a treatment
yesterday at 4:17 p.m.
Well, not a medical treatment.
Braddock was under
my exclusive care.
And not to be indelicate, agent
but when do I get access
to the body?
- Access?
- I need to examine it.
Obtain tissue samples
for my research.
I-it's all part of the agreement
our patients sign
when they join the study.
Uh, you're gonna have to
take that up with the coroner
and she's working on
another case.
Might keep her busy
for a few days.
I see.
- Excuse me.
- Oh.
Allow me.
- Oh, well, thank you, handsome.
- Hmm.
Take my advice.
Don't get cancer.
Well, that sounds like
good advice.
Although you do seem spry
despite all.
You know, why not?
Western wisdom says
I should have been dead
nine months ago,
but look.
I made it
to the bonus round.
You credit the drugs here?
- Could be the drugs.
- Could be the tea.
You know about the tea?
Yeah, I could smell it
in your handbag.
No, no, no, no need, I got a
very strong whiff of it
in Archer Braddock's kitchen.
I heard about Archer
this morning.
Were-were you a friend?
Oh, no, no, no. I'm helping
the police solve the murder.
Oh. Well, I was the one
who told Archer about the tea.
I saw him a few weeks back,
and he wasn't looking so good.
You know, he had this
air of finality hanging over him
like a piano on a wire.
Mm-hm...where would
one buy a tin
of that stinky tea
if they had to?
[Lisbon]
'Who closes shop
in the middle of the day?'
[Patrick]
'Mmm.'
[instrumental music]
[door clicks open]
They probably just forgot
to flip the sign.
Hello?
Is anyone here?
What's the goal here,
anyway?
So Braddock drinks
stinky tea.
People who are dying
will try anything.
Well, the stuff that Braddock
tried was working
'or so he thought.'
What, you think that has
something to do with his murder?
No idea, but if Braddock
found the cure for cancer
I want in on it.
- Good luck with that.
- Shh!
[muffled groaning]
[whimpering and groaning]
[Patrick mutters]
[woman groaning loudly]
'Help me.'
[woman crying]
- 'Help me. Helpme.'
- Stay back.
[panting]
Help me!
[Lisbon]
'Police!'
Please. Calm your spirits.
It's okay. Everything's fine.
[woman panting]
Shh.
- What are you doing?
- What are youdoing?
[instrumental music]
[speaking inaudibly]
[indistinct conversations]
Welcome.
I'm Brother Josef.
Oh, and I am not a hugger.
[chuckles]
Patrick Jane. Nice to meet you.
That was a wonderful show.
How much do you charge
for that show?
- No show. A healing.
- Hmm.
And my temple
accepts donations.
Uh, it's entirely
up to you.
Ahh. Another nonprofit.
Smart act.
[chuckles]
I get that reaction a lot.
But the healing powers
of the sun
have been well-documented.
- Then where does the tea fit?
- Tea?
Yeah, the stinky red stuff,
curls the nose hairs.
[chuckles]
You're talking about
the tea of clarity.
It's pretty foul stuff.
I had to take it
off our shelves recently.
- Too many customer complaints.
- What's in it?
A proprietary blend of nettles,
herbs, and possibility.
And how much does that
go for these days?
[chuckles]
You have me all wrong.
I am a rich man
but you won't find
my wealth in any bank account.
I sell just enough teas
and holistic remedies
to keep my temple doors open.
And did you open them
to this man?
Sure. Archer.
We just performed
his final healing ceremony.
At 4:17?
That's when the solar flares
were at their peak.
And what were you healing?
His cancer, of course.
We channel the solar corona
to target cancerous tumors.
We had many tries
with Archer
but we, we finally got 'em all.
And all of his money.
Archer didn't pay me
a penny, Mr. Jane.
Well, except for the tea.
Mmm. Is that why
you killed him?
Excuse me?
What?
Archer Braddock is dead.
He was murdered
right after he left here.
Oh, no. Oh, no, no, no.
Not after all he fought through.
After all our work.
Oh, my God.
[sighs]
His-his reflexes
were better.
His-his-his
pressure was way down.
He had a-he had a ruddy,
healthy glow in his cheeks.
- That part of the act?
- Hard to say.
It's all so theatrical.
Did Braddock say where he was
going when he was leaving?
No, no. I-I have no idea.
His transition from this world
was corrupted by violence.
- I need to see his body.
- Why?
To release his energy so he can
cross over peacefully.
Maybe at the funeral.
In the meantime,
you're gonna tell us
everything that happened
yesterday.
Of course.
Yeah, I have that.
Okay. Sure.
This is Cho.
It's Summer.
Hey.
I just wanted to apologize
for making you late.
It's okay. You were only
trying to help.
How can I make it
up to you?
[chuckles]
I'm sure you'll
think of something.
Hey, Cho.
I gotta go.
I'll call you later.
Okay.
That was Agua Blanca PD.
They found the victim's car.
It was about a block away
from that banquet hall
where Aden gave us the slip.
Well, Braddock's last phone call
was to Aden.
So maybe father and son had a
reunion that didn't go so well.
Wouldn't be surprised.
I talked to the estate lawyer.
Most of Braddock's money
was split into trusts
for Liesl and Aden, payable
on their 23rd birthdays.
Sounds normal.
Rich normal, anyway.
Yeah, but in light
of his son's drug problems
Braddock was in
the process of changing
the age of Aden's trust
from 23 to 30.
So Aden confronts Braddock.
Argument breaks out.
Aden chokes dad
and buries the body.
- We need to find that kid.
- Yeah.
Rigsby, can you hold?
Well, he has to collect
his pay, right?
Why don't we stake out
the banquet hall?
Aden was a part-timer,
minimum wage.
He's not gonna risk getting
caught for that paycheck.
Can we track
his cell phone?
Tried. It's powered off.
What about the lottery scam?
I don't know. I think
he's too smart for that.
Hey, who's this?
Sorry to keep you waiting.
Aden Braddock?
Uh, yeah.
Sure, you can.
Yeah, you can come in
and talk to us.
Let me give you the address.
Why'd you run, Aden?
I don't know.
[exhales]
Okay, I do. I was carrying
drugs, okay?
I couldn't get popped again. It
would have been my third strike.
So instead you'll be
charged with obstruction.
- A felony offense.
- I wasn't thinking straight.
I'd just found out
my father was killed.
Liesl called me.
Look.
I need you
to come clean with me.
When was the last time
you talked to your father?
I don't know. Months?
Okay, look.
We're getting off
to a bad start here.
He called you
at 7:45 last night.
[Archer Braddock]
Hey, kiddo, it's dad.
It's been a while.
I didn't wanna hear it.
You said "Talk to."
That's a message
and I didn't wanna hear it.
You know whose car was found
a block away from your job?
I wasn't working last night.
Ask anybody.
Well, maybe he thought
youwereworking
and someone followed him.
Who might that be?
Oh, no.
- I have this friend.
- Friend?
Dealer.
Mike Tran.
Lately, he's been
asking a lot of questions
about my dad, like..
...how much he's worth
and what kind of cars he sells.
- And you told him?
- Why wouldn't I?
I hated my father.
He cut me off and..
...yeah.
I'm not talking about money.
He left me.
[instrumental music]
No sign of Tran.
Cho?
'How's it looking back there?'
I got nothing
going on back here.
Aden's dealer's
a nasty piece of business.
Two charges aggravated assault
intent to distribute meth
and he choked out
a probation officer.
It's worth checking out.
You sure he'll be here?
His baby-mother says he was
dropping off some money today.
He can be your role model.
[scoffs]
Did you know your husband
was seeing Brother Josef?
Archer's cancer made him..
...a target for
quite a few con men
'and alternative remedies.'
Why didn't you tell us?
Forgive me for trying
to maintain a man's dignity.
We have a cancer
charity in our name
that we've raised
a lot of money for.
Did you know that
he was getting better?
Yeah.
The same way
he was getting better
after the oxygen therapy
in Germany
or the psychic surgery
in Brazil.
It was a constant
roller coaster ride with Archer.
Chemo, huh?
Kills the appetite.
- How about a spot of tea?
- Oh, that sounds lovely.
You got it.
[instrumental music]
Suspect has arrived.
Time to move.
Cho?
You copy?
[glass shattering]
Sounds like a fight.
I'm going in.
Go! Go!
Go!
Police!
[crying]
You're safe.
It's okay.
Is he there?
[gunshot]
[grunting]
[Kimball Cho]
'Stay down!'
Weapon's secure.
- You good?
- Yeah.
[Kimball Cho]
'Get up.'
Guess it was my lucky day.
Mrs. Braddock is still
upstairs waiting for her tea.
What are you doing?
Oh, just, uh, enjoying
the calm before the storm.
You only made
one cup of tea.
Mm. I needed to keep
those tea bags dry.
I'm not gonna like this, am I?
You're gonna love it.
[Lisbon]
'Oh, ho!'
[instrumental music]
You may wanna cover your ears.
[beeping]
Liesl!
Somebody help me!
Showtime.
[beeping]
Fire!
She moves pretty good
for a cancer patient.
Oh, it's a miracle.
Sister Helen has been healed!
Ma'am!
What kind of woman fakes cancer?
Lots of women go to
extremes to meet men.
Extremes, yes.
Cancer support groups, no.
I was lucky to have Archer
for the time that I did.
He opened doors in me that
I didn't even know existed.
He was caring,
generous, spiritual.
Rich...and dying fast.
The perfect man.
How did you know?
That I didn't have cancer?
Well, you lacked a..
'...an air of finality.'
Plus you shaved your head
but your vanity prevented you
from losing the eyebrows.
Devil's in the details.
Braddock's insurance policy.
It was recently changed
to add a new beneficiary.
- You.
- I didn't kill Archer.
You had 5 million reasons
to want him dead.
Archer had a month left, maybe.
Why would I risk losing all
of that money to take his life?
I don't know.
Doyou?
She's telling the truth.
You can go.
- No. She can't.
- You can't.
- Why not?
- I'm charging you with fraud.
What?
You're not gonna see a dime
of that insurance money.
And your face is gonna be
plastered all over the news.
But at least
you'll have your eyebrows.
Let's see how many
dates you get then.
Yeah.
- Do you feel better?
- I do.
Yeah, good.
Now it's my turn.
I have a plan
to catch our killer.
Can't wait to hear that.
[instrumental music]
He looks so thin..
...fragile.
When was the last time
you saw him?
A year ago.
When he told us
about the diagnosis.
It ended with us fighting
and Liesl crying.
How does that happen?
Ran down Tran's alibi.
But he was 40 miles away
when your father was killed.
- So Tran didn't do it?
- No.
But we do have a suspect.
One whose alibi doesn't hold up.
Does the name
"Dolores" ring any bells?
The waitress
at the banquet hall?
[Rigsby]
'You told me you weren't
at work last night'
but Dolores says
you stopped by around eight
to borrow some money.
- You lied.
- No, I didn't.
I told you I wasn't working.
I didn't say
I wasn't at work.
You know, it's all lies
and half-truths with you.
How are we supposed to
know what to believe?
Look, I needed money
for the drugs, okay?
And I needed drugs
after I saw that my dad called.
He had this way of
making me feel so small.
Not anymore.
I didn't kill him.
- You have to believe me.
- No, we don't.
Give me your hands.
Science never sleeps
around here, does it?
Mr. Jane,
how may I help you?
Well, I don't need
your services...thankfully.
Even if I did,
I'm not sure
this is the first place,
I'd come.
I met this fellow,
Brother Josef
who can, uh, totally
eradicate bone cancer.
Really? How so?
The power of positive thinking.
Naturally.
That's right, naturally.
No drugs whatsoever.
That's how
he cured Archer Braddock.
- Is that what this man claims?
- Yeah.
Betsy, pull up
Braddock's file.
Uh, certainly.
'Let me show you
something, Mr. Jane.'
This is Braddock's last MRI,
taken two weeks ago.
You see all those white spots?
- Yeah, looks like a snowstorm.
- It's cancer.
It spread from his bones and was
working its way to his lungs.
He had five weeks, max.
Oh, this was taken
two weeks ago.
Maybe that cancer's cleared up.
The mind is
a very powerful tool.
Well, I'm happy to
show you personally
when I'm granted
access to the body.
Where are we at
with my request?
Oh, I still can't
reach the coroner.
Everyone wants to look
inside that body.
Brother Josef
had the same request.
Did you approve it?
Well, I'll tell you what
I told Brother Josef.
It's out of my hands.
But my boss has called in
a forensic pathologist
from Sacramento.
He'll be performing
a full autopsy
first thing in
the morning.
I'll let you know
what he finds.
Well..
Oh, hey.
I wanted to, uh, show you this.
We need to talk about
what happened today.
I was late covering
your back. I'm sorry.
- You're sorry?
- It won't happen again.
Cho, you saved my life.
You were there
when I needed you.
I owe you...big time.
No.
You don't owe me anything.
Okay.
This is too creepy.
Killers like creepy.
I can't feel my feet.
They're freezing.
Be patient.
Has it ever occurred to you that
maybe your theory was wrong?
Nope.
Braddock's killer buried him
because there was something
about the body,
he didn't want people to know.
So if we put out
the word of an autopsy
then we force the killer
to try again.
If we don't die
of frostbite first.
Can you wiggle your toes?
Because if you can wiggle
your toes, you're fine.
- I can't move them--
- Shh. Shh.
Someone is comin'.
Oh!
Surprise, surprise.
You're under arrest for
the murder of Archer Braddock.
What's going on?
I didn't killArcher!
Then why were you
tryin' to steal his body?
I'm not stealing him, either.
I told you, I need
to perform a ritual
to release the bad energy before
his journey to the afterlife.
There was something inside
Braddock, wasn't there?
Something that would
lead directly to you
if the coroner
discovered it.
You never did share
the proprietary blend
of that stinky special
tea of yours, did you?
The tea of clarity?
It was killing him
quicker than the cancer.
That's why
you stopped selling it.
Oh, please. You're making
a terrible mistake.
So you say, Brother Josef.
At least let me
release his spirit.
Let me do that for him, please.
Let's go.
Hands behind your back.
So the amount of radiation
released from a solar flare
can damage satellites?
It's way, way more powerful
than the radiation therapy
used to treat cancer.
Did you know this, Lisbon?
- Fascinating.
- Now, listen.
Aren't I allowed a-a, uh,
a phone call or something?
In a minute.
Sit down.
[cellphone ringing]
Excuse me.
Lisbon.
Are you sure?
No. No, we didn't take it.
We'll be right there.
Get everybody out of that room.
It's a crime scene now.
Braddock's body is
missing from the morgue.
They think somebody
stole it after we left.
Oh, dear.
He was right about one thing.
We just made a terrible mistake.
[instrumental music]
No sign of the killer
or Braddock's body.
Whoever took it won't make
the same mistake twice.
They'll want to destroy
the body...quickly.
How would you do
that in Agua Blanca?
I can think of one way.
Please tell me it doesn't
involve feeding tigers.
Tigers leave bones.
There is a more thorough option.
[Lisbon]
'I hope
you're right about this.'
Look at this clinic.
Very well funded.
Scheck's ego would require
that he has the best.
'I tell you, this guy'
is gonna have a top of
the line medical incinerator.
In the basement?
Can we use inside
voices, please?
[instrumental music]
Police!
Drop the...weapon.
Better late than never,
I suppose.
Hands in the air!
Your hands, not his.
[Jane]
'Oh!'
Did you act alone?
Did Dr. Scheck have
anything to do with this?
No.
He'd never pull off..
...never mind.
It'll go a lot easier
if you just come clean.
We looked at
your bank statements.
You're very wealthy
for a nurse.
Cancer survivors are often
grateful to their caregivers.
You took bribes, didn't you?
Cancer studies
are like lotteries
and you were selling
the winning tickets.
- You were selling hope.
- It's cheap at the price.
Why were you trying to
destroy Archer Braddock's body?
His liver was damaged.
Alcoholism.
And you missed it.
Oh, we thought Brother Josef
was poisoning him with his tea
when in fact
it was your drug.
Because of the liver damage,
it was killing him
faster than the cancer.
I knew Dr. Scheck would find out
in his postmortem exam.
And then there would be
a whole investigation.
And...they'd have
found out about..
...about the gifts
I received from patients.
I had to do something.
So you went to
the banquet hall that night.
You followed him there.
He was gonna die anyway..
...of bone cancer.
Do you know
how agonizing that is?
Excruciatingly slow and painful.
[crackling]
[Betsy]
I made his passing easy.
A little chloroform
before I suffocated him
he never felt a thing.
I ended his suffering.
It was an act
of kindness, really.
I think Mr. Braddock and his
children would beg to differ.
[Van Pelt]
'What you got there?'
Huh.
It's my kid.
- So big so fast.
- Mm.
Only a couple weeks to go.
I heard about today.
Are you okay?
Yeah.
You know,
when that guy shot at me
all I could think about
was how I gotta make it out
to see my son.
It's crazy.
You know, if I'd died a year ago
it wouldn't have
mattered so much
in the big scheme of things.
- It would have mattered to me.
- Yeah.
Not as much as it would
have mattered to him.
He's a game changer.
He's a lucky kid.
Here we go.
What's this for?
Well, to let you know what
a proper cup of tea smells like
before you go out
into the world.
Brother Josef really did
a number on my dad, huh?
Oh, I don't know.
He gave him hope.
No better way
to stimulate the body
than the promise of a new day.
And Helen?
I still can't believe that.
I did a cancer walk
for that bitch.
Language.
Liesl?
Aden?
I-I talked to Aunt Marcia and..
...I wanna move back home.
- Okay.
- After rehab.
Who talked you into that?
Dad.
[Archer Braddock]
Hey, kiddo, it's dad.
It's been a while.
Look, I'm outside your job.
I made a mistake.
I want you to come home.
Whatever time I have left
I wanna spend
with you and Liesl.
I love you both so much.
Okay. See you soon, I hope.
Here goes.
Come on, let's go home.
Mr. Jane?
Thanks.
- Boss, you have a minute?
- Sure.
I heard about you and Rigsby
with the drug dealer earlier.
Nice work.
Is everything alright?
No.
This is a safe room.
You can talk about
whatever you'd like here.
Okay.
[instrumental music]
I'm sorry,
I was late this morning.
I'll make sure
it never happens again.
Okay.
Goodnight, boss.
[instrumental music]
[music continues]
[toilet flushes]
[theme music]